SWAPNANIL SINHA

Bangalore, KA, India

+91-88672-72279 | swapnanilsinha21@gmail.com

<u>LinkedIn Profile</u> | <u>Github Profile</u> | <u>My Portfolio</u> | <u>Leetcode Profile</u>

SUMMARY

A full-stack developer with 3+ years of experience in JavaScript, React.js, Node.js, MYSQL, with expertise in data structures and algorithms, Git versioning, Linux, Grafana, front-end and backend development, clients & stakeholder management and technofunctional roles.

EXPERIENCE

Comviva Technologies | Senior Software Engineer

Jan 2022 - Present

Developed scalable APIs and USSD value-added services for mobile banking systems, aligning with streamlined software development life cycle practices.

- Implemented user-friendly web features for the LEAP product utilizing **Node.js and React.js**, ensuring a seamless, pixel-perfect user interface with integrated HTML and CSS.
- Analyzed complex time-series data from InfluxDB and created dynamic **KPI dashboards** using Grafana, transforming intricate data into actionable insights.

Ckuens Analytics | Data Science Intern

Jul 2021 - Sep 2021

Engineered machine learning models using Python to classify and predict heartbeat signal anomalies with rigorous testing and validation.

• Processed and analyzed large datasets with NumPy, Pandas, and Matplotlib, delivering actionable insights and presenting findings to senior management.

PROJECTS

Hotel Bookings Management Application | Visit

Aug 2024 - Sep 2024

- Developed an Airbnb-inspired user interactive web application on **Vercel**, **utilizing TypeScript and Next.js** for a seamless user experience. Utilized Git for version control throughout the project, with the repository publicly accessible.
- Created the interface using the shaden/ui library, and efficiently handled user, property, and booking data with **Prisma DB**, built on PostgreSQL/ MongoDB.
- Integrated user account management using Clerk API and payment processing using the Stripe API.

LEAP Studio Platform Feature Improvement | Comviva Technologies

Jan 2024 - Present

- Developed and deployed features from inception to testing, elevating Leap to an enterprise-level tool.
- Rapidly developed and implemented new features using React, Express, and Node.js.
- Features received positive feedback and have boosted customer productivity by upto 35%.

Airtel Money | Comviva Technolgies

Aug 2024 - Present

- Designed and implemented a user-friendly interface to manage Merchant and Subscriber financial transactions.
- Set up dedicated Leap instances to ensure secure and interference-free monetary transactions for users across 14 countries.
- Successfully integrated UNO-FLARES, Mobiquity, and Leap Studio for seamless system interoperability.

Abhi Skill - Upskilling Platform

Jul 2020 - May 2021

• Created an online skill-based learning platform for blue-collar workers to upskill and establish a community around their skills.

SKILLS

- Frontend Development: HTML, CSS, React.js, Next.js
- Backend & Frameworks: Node.js, Express.js, Authentication, Microservices
- Programming Languages: JavaScript, TypeScript, Python
- Databases: SQL, InFluxDB, Redis, MongoDB
- Tools & Technologies: Linux, Git Versioning, Grafana, Microsoft Office, Data Structures and Algorithms, AWS

EDUCATION

SRM Institute of Science and Technology

Jun 2018 - May 2022

Bachelor of Technology in Electronics and Communication Engineering (GPA: 8.53 / 10.0)

Achievements

- Hackathon 23 | Runner up for developing a demo chatbot for Leap. Users could interact with the bot to ge tips, data samples, and screenshots, enabling a understanding of how to navigate and utilize the tool effectively.
- Aarush 2019 | Organized a four-day technical event during the college fest, attracting over 150 attendees and ensuring its seamless execution. The were challenged to design an inertial working model of a Rube Goldberg machine using everyday objects.